- question: "Which data structure in Python is commonly used in Ansible for organizing key-value pairs?"
  day: 2
  answers:
    - Dictionaries
    - Lists
    - JSON files
    - YAML files

- question: "What data structure in Python is used to represent an ordered collection of items?"
  day: 2
  answers:
    - Dictionaries
    - Lists
    - JSON files
    - YAML files

- question: "Which file format is commonly used for human-readable data serialization in Ansible?"
  day: 2
  answers:
    - XML
    - YAML
    - CSV
    - JSON

- question: "In Ansible, what term is used to represent a piece of Python code that performs specific actions or operations and can be executed within a playbook?"
  day: 2
  answers:
    - Inventory
    - Play
    - Task
    - Module

- question: "What is a key distinction between JSON and YAML in the context of Ansible?"
  day: 2
  answers:
    - JSON is more human-readable than YAML.
    - YAML supports complex data structures, while JSON does not.
    - JSON is commonly used for configuration files, while YAML is used for data serialization.
    - YAML allows comments, whereas JSON does not.

- question: "What feature in Ansible allows you to package and distribute content such as roles, modules, and plugins?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Collections
    - Dynamic Inventory
    - Ansible Lint
    - AWX modules

- question: "Which command-line tool is used to fetch Ansible content available on the Ansible Galaxy community hub?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - ansible-builder
    - ansible-runner
    - Molecule
    - ansible-galaxy

- question: "How can you automatically generate inventory for Ansible from external systems or scripts?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Using static files
    - Using YAML syntax
    - Using dynamic inventory
    - Using Molecule

- question: "Which of the following is NOT an example of a best practice when working with Ansible?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Writing modular and reusable playbooks.
    - Using version control to manage Ansible code.
    - Avoiding the use of hardcoded values in playbooks.
    - Running playbooks with elevated privileges using 'sudo'.

- question: "Which tool is commonly used in the Ansible ecosystem to facilitate the testing and development of roles?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Galaxy
    - Terraform
    - Molecule
    - Jenkins

- question: "What tool helps in identifying and automatically fixing potential issues in Ansible playbooks?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Ansible Lint
    - AWX modules
    - Pull Requests
    - Deploying Kubernetes with Ansible

- question: "What does the abbreviation 'CI/CD' stand for in the context of Ansible?"
  day: 3
  answers:
    - Control Interface/Command Directive
    - Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment
    - Container Image/Deployment
    - Configuration Item/Deployment

- question: "Which tool is specifically designed for executing Ansible playbooks, roles, and modules in a controlled and isolated environment?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - Ansible Tower
    - AWX
    - ansible-runner
    - Ansible Galaxy

- question: "Which tool is used to package and build custom Ansible execution environments, including dependencies and runtime configuration?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - Ansible Tower
    - AWX
    - ansible-runner
    - ansible-builder

- question: "What is the purpose of an Ansible Execution Environment?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - To manage the execution of Ansible playbooks on remote hosts.
    - To provide a controlled and consistent runtime environment for Ansible.
    - To store and manage Ansible roles, modules, and plugins.
    - To enable communication between Ansible and external systems.

- question: "In the context of Ansible and automation triggers, what is a WebHook?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - A type of Ansible module used for web scraping.
    - A Python library for building Ansible playbooks.
    - An HTTP callback that enables external systems to trigger Ansible actions.
    - A configuration file used to define Ansible inventory.

- question: "In GitLab, what is the name of the file used to define Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipelines?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - .gitignore
    - .gitlab-ci.yml
    - .gitconfig
    - .gitattributes

- question: "Which tool provides a web-based graphical interface, role-based access control, and job scheduling for managing and executing Ansible playbooks?"
  day: 4
  answers:
    - Ansible Galaxy
    - Ansible Runner
    - Ansible Tower
    - Ansible Builder
















